Byron Brown

(814) 599-6428 401 Mapleview Dr Apt 1B Pittsburgh, PA 15220 <u>byronrb92@gmail.com</u> <u>www.linkedin.com/in/byron-r-brown</u> <u>https://github.com/doctorbebo</u> <u>https://doctorbebo.github.io/portfolio/</u>

Summary:

I am a full stack developer with a background in music and audio design focused on creating an immersive user experience. I have completed a certificate program from the University of Washington focusing on full stack web development and mastering HTML, CSS, JavaScript, jQuery, React.js, Database Theory, MySQL, and NoSQL with mobile-first responsive design. I look forward to applying my skills in software development.

Technical Skills:

- C#, JavaScript, HTML, CSS
- React.JS, jQuery, Express.js NODE.js, Bootstrap
- MySQL, NoSQL, MongoDB
- Unity Game Engine
- Git, GitHub

Projects:

Fair Weather Hiking:

https://fair-weather-hiking.herokuapp.com/

- After creating an account and logging in, this website will help narrow your search for the best hike in the area based on your location.
- Technologies: React, HTML, CSS, Materialize, JavaScript, Express, MongoDB, Mongoose, and Passport

Progressive Web App Budget Tracker:

https://still-eyrie-21891.herokuapp.com/

- This is an easy to use budget tracker that functions while both online and offline for a more seamless experience.
- Technologies: IndexedDB, Ajax, and Express APIs.
 HTML, CSS, JavaScript.

Note Taker App:

https://afternoon-chamber-95392.herokuapp.com/

- This simple note taker app saves, deletes, and edits notes. Notes are saved in a server for user convenience.
- Technologies: HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, JavaScript, and Express API.

Education:

Certificate in Web Development, May 2020 University of Washington, Seattle, WA

B.A., Commercial Music: Film Scoring May 2017 Liberty University, Lynchburg, VA

Experience:

Office Administrator (Sound Deli Provisions) Woodinville, WA, Jan 2019 – Apr 2020

- Implemented new weekly inventory system that increased speed by 75%
- Applied new ordering practices that decreased errors significantly
- Effective data entry & customer service

Software Developer (Donation Games) Redmond, WA, May 2019 – Dec 2019

- Efficiently programmed all game mechanics and features using C# and Unity game engine
- Conceptualized original game and mechanics
- Designed stylish UI
- Released game on Google Play Store

Sound Designer, Music Composer (Devs on a Boat) Seattle, WA, July 2019 – Nov 2019

- Reliably and remotely met with the dev team weekly to discuss accomplishments and goals
- Consistently met deadlines with excellence
- Composed, orchestrated, and mastered original music
- Designed, mixed, and mastered sound effects